<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>/home/vineet</title><link href="http://naiquevin.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://naiquevin.github.io/feeds/erlang.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://naiquevin.github.io/</id><updated>2012-07-21T18:14:00+05:30</updated><entry><title>Erlang is next, Clojure shall wait</title><link href="http://naiquevin.github.io/erlang-is-next-clojure-shall-wait.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-07-21T18:14:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Vineet Naik</name></author><id>tag:naiquevin.github.io,2012-07-21:erlang-is-next-clojure-shall-wait.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A few weeks back, when I was close to completing chapter 1 exercises
of &lt;a href="http://mitpress.mit.edu/sicp/"&gt;SICP&lt;/a&gt;, I had decided that after
completing this chapter, I would take some time off it to learn
Clojure. If you ask why Clojure, then frankly speaking, because it's
being talked about a lot these days. At the same time, having watched
a couple of brilliant talks by it's author
&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/richhickey"&gt;Rick Hickey&lt;/a&gt; and having come across
&lt;a href="https://github.com/technomancy/leiningen"&gt;some&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https://github.com/noir-clojure/noir"&gt;of&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https://github.com/clojure/clojurescript"&gt;the&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://mad.emotionull.com/"&gt;cool&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https://github.com/overtone/overtone"&gt;stuff&lt;/a&gt; that the Clojure fellows
are building and the
&lt;a href="https://github.com/overtone/emacs-live"&gt;way they are using emacs&lt;/a&gt; for
it, it makes me believe that Clojure completely lives upto the
hype. BTW, I have started loving lisp courtesy of Scheme and Emacs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I have completed the SICP chapter 1 exercises and as planned I
am going to start learning a new language. This new language is
however &lt;a href="http://www.erlang.org/"&gt;Erlang&lt;/a&gt; and not Clojure!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what happened? Last week I felt a strong urge to learn Erlang. I
thought, learning some basics would do no harm and went ahead with
&lt;a href="http://learnyousomeerlang.com/"&gt;LYSE&lt;/a&gt;. On second thought, I realized
that diving deep into erlang at this point of time might not be a bad
idea after all. Over the last few months I have been working with the
&lt;a href="http://www.ejabberd.im/"&gt;Ejabberd XMPP server&lt;/a&gt; at work. With no
significant erlang knowledge I have been able to configure it greatly
(All credit for which goes to the ever helpful ejabberd community and
it's well documented config file!). Not only that, I have been able to
help "newer-bies" on the ejabberd mailing list in whatever way I can
for eg. pointing them to documentation etc. But to someone like me, an
outsider coming from a Python background, Erlang looks like a weird
language with a weird syntax (IMO more weird than what lisp seemed at
first). Not knowing Erlang can be very limiting if I want to seriously
achieve anything with Ejabberd. So I have come to the conclusion that
if I don't learn erlang now, it would be like being dishonest with
both myself and ejabberd!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the otherside, if I learn Clojure, one of the following things are
likely to happen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will have my aha! moments in Clojure and after solving some
exercises I never really use it for anything non-trivial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would absolutely fall in love with Clojure and want to use it
more and more. But there is a slight problem here. There is no real
chance I can start using it at work anytime in the near future because
it takes a lot for a team of programmers to embrace a non-mainstream
language like Clojure. Sure, I would use it for a couple of side
projects but from my experience, the chance that these projects would
solve a real problem is rather remote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you notice that I haven't mentioned "Not liking Clojure" as one of
the possibility? That's because I don't think I will not like it :) again
because of the same reasons I have stated earlier. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So my next language is going to be Erlang. Well, atleast I am going to
make a determined effort for a month (while trying hard not to give in
everytime some Clojure library or article gets featured on Hacker
News!) But I will continue to solve SICP exercises as I find it
relaxing as an after work activity. All pending work on my Python,
PHP, Javascript side projects gets done this weeekend and in the
coming week, looking forward to meet you erlang, Clojure shall wait.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry></feed>