<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>/home/vineet - history</title><link href="http://naiquevin.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://naiquevin.github.io/feeds/history.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://naiquevin.github.io/</id><updated>2017-08-13T00:00:00+05:30</updated><entry><title>Dan Carlin's Blueprint for Armageddon</title><link href="http://naiquevin.github.io/dan-carlins-blueprint-for-armageddon.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-08-13T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-08-13T00:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Vineet Naik</name></author><id>tag:naiquevin.github.io,2017-08-13:/dan-carlins-blueprint-for-armageddon.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Podcast recommendation&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently finished listening to
&lt;a href="http://www.dancarlin.com/home-hh-54/"&gt;Blueprint for Armageddon&lt;/a&gt;, a
podcast series from
&lt;a href="http://www.dancarlin.com/hardcore-history-series/"&gt;Dan Carlin's Hard Core History&lt;/a&gt;. In
a total of ~22 hours across 6 episodes, it takes you through World War
I in painful detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of merely presenting historical events as facts, he talks
about the political and social situations that led to the conflicts
and quotes from the memoirs of many historians, generals, soldiers and
common people describing the extreme human conditions, both physical
and psychological, on the battle field as well as the "home front". In
spite of it's length, it's entertaining to the point that it feels
almost like fiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's a lot of content packed into each episode though and sometimes
it did get a bit confusing chronologically. But understandably, it was
a multi-front war with too many things happening at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a history podcast Carlin does a great job at presenting it in a
with an overall unbiased and balanced view. The most amazing part is
where he occasionally makes you put yourself in the shoes of those who
lived the horrors of the war - the victims as well as the
perpetrators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At several occasions while listening to it, I remembered a quote I had
read somewhere before (but don't remember where exactly) -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"One thing that we should definitely learn from history is the consequence of not learning from history".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am glad I discovered this podcast and am grateful to my friend who
told me about it. Can't recommend it enough!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="podcasts"></category><category term="history"></category></entry></feed>