<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>/home/vineet - projects</title><link href="http://naiquevin.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://naiquevin.github.io/feeds/projects.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://naiquevin.github.io/</id><updated>2009-05-28T16:53:18+05:30</updated><entry><title>My first website goes live..and I am so excited!</title><link href="http://naiquevin.github.io/my-first-website-goes-liveand-i-am-so-excited.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-05-28T16:53:18+05:30</published><updated>2009-05-28T16:53:18+05:30</updated><author><name>Vineet Naik</name></author><id>tag:naiquevin.github.io,2009-05-28:/my-first-website-goes-liveand-i-am-so-excited.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: This post exists for historical reasons! The website I had
built is no longer up and I gave up the domain name. I may have lost
the source code too :-(&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally I managed to put a substantial work online. My first website
&lt;a href="http://www.noiseokplease.com"&gt;Noise OK Please&lt;/a&gt; (broken link) has just been
launched. This is an online community for musicians and their fans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One special thing about this particular project is that no platform
has been used. All the code has been written by me. Apart from this,
whatever you will find on this website is my own work (Except the
avatars. The southpark avatar comes from
&lt;a href="http://www.sp-studio.de"&gt;sp-studio.de&lt;/a&gt;). Of course, I have used a lot
of references for accomplishing the task, such as books and no need to
mention the greatest resource of the present day - Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One may ask, why did I try to re-invent the wheel? Its because the
main intention behind this project is to learn though hands on
experience.  Other than that I wanted to have my own work to show it
to recruiters so that they can offer me some cool jobs! :).  As the
number of users increase, I will be re-building it on some platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The website may seem like an internet startup in the first glance. But
as of yet, business is not the first thing I am looking at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There still lot of work to be done yet. Some things in the pipe line
are,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Invite facility to let users invite others to join the community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An interface to search users based on various criteria. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A JavaScript powered WYSIWYG rich text editor to post on the wall. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And much more.. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would also like to mention a few references that helped a lot&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.webmasterworld.com"&gt;webmasterworld forums &lt;/a&gt; where
  professional developers were kind enough to answer my silliest of
  doubts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A beautiful book called Head First PHP &amp;amp; MySQL.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Online tutorials from&lt;a href="http://w3schools.com"&gt; w3schools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS&amp;gt; If you stumble upon this blog post please take some time to look
at the website and give me an honest feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PPS&amp;gt; If you are a web developer, your feedback and comments are
extremely valuable.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="social networking"></category><category term="noise ok please"></category><category term="musician community"></category><category term="web development"></category></entry></feed>